So we're going to go back to your index.html page
that you were playing around with with your characters.
And this time, under each of your character,
I want you to go ahead and add a favorite button to it.
And when a user clicks on that favorite button,
go ahead and update a separate list that tracks your favorite characters.
And as a bonus, if you have some time,
go ahead and actually create a form that will allow you to add more characters
to whatever the preset of data already exists.
Cool. So what I'm going to do now for the solution
is we're going to go ahead and run through this.
Okay. So inside of my index.html file.
All right. First thing we're going to do is we're going to add a button to each character.
Well, we have our list here that we have.
And all we're going to do is I'm going to do this.
I'm going to just, for the sake of making it easier,
let's make the p element wrapping around that.
So we save that. This is good.
And then we can then go ahead and add a button.
So just do.
And I'm going to add a star here for favorite.
There we go. We have a favorite button. Great.
Now, what we need to do is actually add a favorite character.
So at click, we will say favorite character.
We haven't written the method yet.
So we'll go down inside of our app here.
And so inside of data, we don't need that.
So we need it here.
So we need methods for favorite character.
And this is where the argument actually comes into play.
Because at this point, well, there's a couple things.
One, we need a favorite list.
So I like to try to go alphabetical whenever it makes sense.
So favorite list, that's just an array.
And so what we want to do is we're going to do this.favoriteList.push.
What are we pushing?
We want to push the character that's actually being called.
And so the way we detect this is we go inside of our favorite character.
And we're in our loop, so we can actually pass character directly to our function.
Which means character now should be here.
And we can go ahead and push that over.
And so to show that that works, let's go ahead and add another list right here.
This time, we'll just add a h2 of favorite characters.
Once again, I see a typo there.
I'll fix that real quick.
v4 character in favorite list.
And then inside of here, we're just going to render out the character.
Okay?
So as we can see here, actually nothing's showing up.
So actually, this is a good instance where we might actually want to do no favorite characters left.
So this is where the vif works well.
So vif favorite characters or favorite lists.length.
Actually, you know what?
I usually prefer the greater than zero as my first one.
So we're going to swap this.
We're going to go down here and we'll swap the vif for the ul
as well because that's my preferred default state.
And this empty state is really a fallback for one that doesn't have it.
There we go.
No favorite characters yet.
We'll be favorite Toph.
There we go.
Toph, Zuko, Aang, Katara.
Everything's working.
Now, of course, you can do deduping and all that fun stuff,
but I'll leave you all to play with that.
And then there you go.
Create form.
Okay.
And then let's go ahead and add the characters as well.
So what we want to do next is we want to actually then add a new character.
How do we do that?
Well, at this point, the easiest thing for me to do
is let's go ahead and create another h2.
And this h2 will be new character.
And then what do we have?
We have basically one attribute, which is the character name.
And so let's say name.
And then we'll have the input.
And this will be text.
That's fine.
And then what we're going to do is we're going to do...
If we think about the data structure we're probably looking for,
eventually characters have more attributes, right?
So if we think about the reactive data we're looking for,
we can say there's going to be a new character object
that we're basically going to be tracking inside of here.
So with that, we can then say vModel equals new character.
And you know what? We actually know how we kind of want it structured.
So we're actually going to go ahead by default,
go ahead and actually define the name inside of the data
so we're clear to future developers that it's not an implicit thing.
And then new character.name.
And so to show that that works, what we're going to do once again
is let's go ahead and use the pre-element.
And so the pre-element is a handy little trick
to actually render your reactive data in a way that's actually readable.
So here I'll show you the difference.
So if we save here and refresh,
you'll see that the name is actually being rendered kind of in its code block form.
But if you didn't do a pre-element and you just did like the p-element, for example,
which is what I might do by default,
you'll see that it basically automatically just renders it as a normal string.
And so the pre-element, it's not as obvious in this particular case,
but when you have like JSON objects that's multiple lists,
it's really nice to have it automatically formatted
with just using an HTML element without having to do anything special.
So there we go.
And now if we come in here, hey, there we go.
Look, things are actually changing.
So once again, if I say appa, right, and then, hmm, nothing's adding yet.
Why?
Because we haven't actually had a way to actually push the character to it.
So how might we do that?
Well, for the sake of showing you all something new, right,
we talked about vModel and all that stuff,
and we know how to do some, we can click on the button to add it.
But what if instead we did something a little bit more fun?
Let's not do a button this time.
What if we wanted to do a key up,
and then when we hit enter, then we push it.
How would that work?
Well, we can actually do an add key up event,
and then we can say basically add new character.
And so if we come in here, and we go to methods,
and we go add new character,
at this point, we do know what the new character is,
so we don't need to pass any arguments to it
because that is already being tracked inside of our reactive data.
So what we get to do is we can do this.characterList.push.
What are we pushing?
We're pushing the new character.
And not just any new character.
It's this new character.
So if we refresh that and do oppa,
you'll see that's weird.
What's happening?
Well, any guesses?
Every key up.
Yep.
Every key up is just like firing off.
It's like add, add, add, add, add, add, add, add, add.
We don't want that.
We really only want to do this when you hit key up enter.
And so some of you are probably thinking,
okay, so I know what I'm going to do.
I'm going to get the event.
I'm going to do event.target,
and then I have to figure out what the key code is.
But I got you all one easier.
Yep.
So the audience already gots it.
So what we can do here,
I mentioned before about modifiers to the API.
On the key up,
Vue also knows we have common things we're using all the time.
And enter and escape keys, those are common.
So all we can do is we do .enter on this.
Refresh.
Oppa's fine.
Hit enter.
And then there you go.
The reason it's blinking is because of that odd character.
So actually, let me,
I think that functionality is basically done.
So let's do-do-do.
Don't do that.
Don't.
Oh, right.
I had that whole list thing.
That's fine.
Okay.
Then if I just add it twice, there you go.
Now you'll see both of them.
And so the final thing,
just from like a code cleanup perspective,
is probably just once we push the character,
just new character equals, you know,
just like a new object.
And so just to prove that that works,
oppa, enter.
That's fine.
Then we can say, like, Azula.
There we go.
Oppa Azula.
And you can see that our name input is being reset properly.